i am an independent director and
chairperson of the board nomination and
committee thank you
[Music]
independent director attending this atm
from my residence in mumbai
good afternoon i am
independent director attending this
agent from my residence in mumbai thank
you
mr sandeep
non-executive non-independent director
attending this agm from icsa bank's
office in mumbai thank you
mr
good afternoon i am
i am sanjeev mantri executive director
attending this agm from icsa lombard
office in mumbai thank you
thank you everyone apart from the board
of directors we also have mr gopal
balachandran chief financial officer and
chief risk officer and mr vikas mehra
company secretary of this company
attending this meeting from this
lnp charge of accountants the joint
statutory auditors of the company have
joined this agm from their respective
locations mr and rupang dollar
designated partner of the
associates llp secretary auditor of the
company
company secretary scrutinizer of this
agent has also joined this agent from
her respective location
i sincerely thank all the shareholders
of the company and joined this meeting
through vc stock or oavm the company has
made necessary arrangements to ensure
participation of members at this meeting
through
omgm and to enable them to vote on the
resolutions effort in the notice
electronically
trust all of you have referred the
general instructions for e-voting and
participation in this meeting in case
members face any difficulty they may
reach out on the helplines given on page
15 of the notice
by
post vc oabm facility for appointment of
proxies by the members was not
applicable and hence the company has not
provided proxy forms to its members and
did not maintain proxy register
the statutory registers other relevant
documents and the annual certificate on
implementation of employee stock options
scheme from practicing company
secretaries of the company are made
available electronically for inspection
by the members during the agm
at nsdl e-voting system
coming to the business of the meeting
with your firm
2013 only the qualifications
observations or adverse remarks of the
auditors on financial track transactions
or matters required to be read out at
the meeting of the shareholders the
joint statutory auditor's report on the
financial statements and the secretarial
audit report for the financial year
ended march 31 2022 do not contain any
qualifications observations or adverse
remarks
accordingly the send reports are not
required to be read at this meeting
for the benefit of the shareholders we
have arranged for an audiovisual
if you dive deeper in every champion
you'll discover
[Music]
the agility to defy adversities
to break their own records and
constantly endeavor to be better
for 21 illustrious years
we at icici lombard have continued
building on our strengths and forging
ahead mightier than ever before
the integration of non-life insurance
business of erstwhile party axa general
insurance with icici lombard general
insurance underlines our belief that we
are better together
braving through the impact of a global
pandemic
we came together with a vision to rise
above the odds
as a unified force we are propelling
forward with another year of healthy
growth registering a revenue of
financial year 2022 that stood off
rupees
179.77 billion continuing on the long
term trajectory
following the successful integration
became second largest general insurance
company in india
this perfect synergy enabled us to clock
a profit of 12.71 billion rupees in 2022
[Music]
we achieved over 29.3 million policies
issued
and settled over 2.3 million claims
our combined ratio stood at 108.8
with return on average equity at 15.4
percent
our stock performance has been
consistent and promising
we strive to be a customer-centric
insurance company
and constantly look for ways to harness
technology to make customers experience
delightful
our recent endeavor to provide a
wellness and insurance platform for our
stakeholders
has led to the creation and deployment
of the revolutionary il take care app
by granting our stakeholders a host of
benefits on the app we are fully
embracing and magnifying our strengths
of customer engagement
[Music]
moreover the two innovative industry
first features face scan and cal scan
were introduced on il take care app
[Music]
with health video calling facility we
are harnessing the power of video
content to create well-crafted customer
service videos
with adoption of web and mobile based
platforms such as ipartner which aids
channel partners in business operations
with digital pos we are facilitating
faster smarter and easier ways to
conduct business for our channel
partners
as an industry leader we are conscious
of leading by example
that is why we deploy organizational
best practices aimed at ensuring
profitable growth using risk selection
and data analytics
as the pandemic effect started raining
and we gradually inched towards normalcy
an evolved way of working was introduced
for our employees
from remote working during the pandemic
we introduced hybrid working model
for seamless work from home arrangement
end-to-end digital enablement is done
with enhanced data and endpoint security
a distinguishing factor that sets us
apart in the insurance industry is our
unceasing effort to achieve greater
levels of environment
social
governance esg
the company installed solar panels in
underprivileged schools in mumbai the
company is committed to reducing its
carbon footprint with initiatives like
recycling e-waste rainwater harvesting
and reducing both electricity and paper
consumption
[Music]
a wellness program named edangeli
focuses on breeding safe drinking water
to children
during the pandemic we reached out to
420 schools
since the program's inception the
company has installed 895 water
purifiers benefiting over two lakh
children
through our flagship initiative right to
safety
we have distributed more than 1.6 lakh
helmets across the country
with our caring hands initiative we are
conducting our checkup and wellness
assessment camps
as the nation reeled from the pandemic
we extended our support by conducting
vaccination drive for more than 50 000
people in mumbai this year cumulatively
our efforts benefited around 4 lakh
people across the nation
we have achieved a guinness book of
world record for our vaccination drive
initiative
a responsible corporate we take pride in
our robust governance practices
ethical business values
policies and compliance framework
the success of any organization depends
on the synergy between each business
function where everyone works together
in perfect synchronicity to deliver
sustainable business growth and
delightful customer experiences that's
when we can score all our goals
together towards victory
[Music]
at icici lombard with our board of
directors
leadership team
employees and every member of our
stakeholder network we are striding
forward with a steadfast mission of
becoming india's foremost general
insurance company
21 years of glory and scripting the
[Music]
future i would like to inform you that
pursuant to the companies act 2013 read
with the relevant rules and semi-listing
regulations the company had provided an
opportunity to all its members
to exercise their voting rights through
electronic voting remote e-booting for
the following items of business to be
transacted at the agm during the period
tuesday august 2 2022 9 am to thursday
august 4 2022 5 pm
members who have not cast their votes
earlier
now i propose to take up the business of
the meeting seriation in accordance with
the agm notice resolutions one to
receive consider and adopt the audited
financial statements of the company for
the financial year ended march 31 2022
2022 together with the reports of the
board of directors and auditors thereon
two
to confirm payment of interim dividend
of rupees for per equity share of the
fight for equity share of the company
for the financial year ended march 31st
four to appoint the director in place of
mr sunday batra deal
03620913 who retires by rotation and
being eligible offers himself for
reappointment
5. to approve remuneration of mrs pkf
sridhara and sultanam llp chartered
accountants and ms chatham company
chartered accountants joined statutory
auditors of the company for fy 2023
special resource 6
appointment of mr rakesh dhaar
bin 007
managing director and ceo of the company
eight revision in the revelation of mr
aloo kumar agarwal diane zero three four
three four three zero four full-time
director designated as executive
director wholesale of the company
nine revision and revelation of mr
sanjeev mantri
drn07192264 full-time director
designated as executive director retail
of the company
10 material related party transactions
for current bank account balances
and purchase of securities from related
parties issued by related or unrelated
parties for fy 24 12
material related party transactions for
sale of securities to related party
issued by related or unrelated parties
for fy24
material related party transactions for
undertaking repurchase repo transactions
and other permitted short-term borrowing
transactions for fy 24 14 material
related party transactions or reverse
rate purchase reverse repo and other
permitted short-term lending
transactions for fy 24
all resolute
partner offending her mr
practicing company secretaries as the
scrutinizer for conducting the e-voting
process
in a fair and transparent manner and to
scrutinize the world's cast through
remote e-voting and e-voting during the
agm and to submit the consolidated
report for voting of voting in
compliance with the provisions of the
companies act 213 and the same
semi-nodr regulations 2015
now i would like to invite speaker
shareholders who have done their prior
registration to speak
members may give their suggestions or
seek clarifications
only those members who are holding
equity shares of the company as on
cutoff date for e-voting that is friday
july 29 2022 uh encouraged to
participate and speak at the agm subject
to prior registration
with due respect to other speakers and
time i respect each speaker to be brief
and restrict their suggestions for
comments to three minutes on matters as
set forth in the notice annual accounts
and operations of a company for fy 2022.
to avoid repetition the answers to all
questions will be provided at the end of
the q a session
i now request the moderator so please go
ahead with the q a session
thank you
this is moderator speaking i request all
the speakers to accept the unmute
request sent by the moderator and turn
on their video while speaking with this
i request the first speaker mrs patel to
please or nude yourself and speak
[Music]
hello
please proceed
uh am i available
yes ma'am you are audible please proceed
thank you
uh respected chairman eminem board of
directors
of my shareholders
and other
shareholders on the
audio video very good afternoon to all
of you i thank um
our
you know company secretary for
this annual report uh as well as the cfo
for a good financial report
um
i just would like to draw the attention
that
um
um anyway i first i would i wish uh
everybody all the very best company
company has done well will also do
further well um now
i i wish the company and all the
employees
for giving us good results uh here i
would like to bring out some few points
htm has firstly meant for the
shareholders
so uh importance is to be given to
shareholders at the time of agm uh board
meeting is meant for the
directors so uh to see the convenience
of the directors more
and more to uh to to keep the
shareholders at up at the time of agm is
not fair company secretary is also a
compliance officer he has to be a link
between the shareholders
and uh
the board
board of directors so uh he has to
maintain connection even with the
shareholders if at the time in the whole
year there is no connection that is
there is there is no link or there is
not even one phone call so from the
secretarial department the whole year
around and at the time of agm
even then we don't receive any call from
the secretarial department this is
something not good
this again is meant for shareholders as
i said before and it is essential that
the secretarial department um at least
a few days earlier say five days or six
years earlier should make a call to the
shareholders at least with the speaker
shareholders
i don't say you might be having
thousands of shareholders it is not
possible to ring up everybody but
because shareholders are hardly 10 or 15
and it is not impossible to ring them up
if u.s company secretary has no time the
poor people working under him it is they
can ring up keep the link that give
importance even to shareholders but many
companies have hosted the personal
um agm
instead of having on oabc
in that we come across and be inferior
here by
avoiding this
the personal uh
agm we are doing it on every c no
problem because people from outside
bombay also can participate in it it is
a very good system but
if it is
physical we can tell them that these are
the problems we are facing from your
secretarial department if we give them a
ring there is no response coming from
their secretarial department now this is
the chevy treatment that shareholders
i'm sure this is not only my complaint
many shareholders complain like that and
just to hear praises or just to hear
showering of all um
shares and such ideas and results
it is not the
venue of the ngf
that it can be conducted in some private
uh meeting but at the agm it is only
the financials to be discussed and the
shareholders must be treated properly
and given importance
i don't say the director should not be
they are the main people who who are the
steering man steering shoe or the
stairman of the ship but at the same
time it is this shareholders meeting it
is not the board meeting
so
not even once in a year if you call if
you keep in touch with the shareholders
it is not good
have you
ever given us hearing at least to me
have you ever given me a ring your
secretary department what compliance
duties have you performed with us
mr secretary
secretary
i don't
computers are not uh very easily
accessible by the all the speakers um
senior citizens it is impossible to go
through the computers
young people can take away the computers
they come home at around 7 7 30 and at
night time before the hour senior
citizens it is very difficult so i
request you to consider all these points
the balance sheet is already over one
year has already completed to discuss
about the finances i want to take out
mistakes on in in the in the
balance sheet on the profit and loss uh
the statements in the
annual report is at least stupidity as
for
what i feel so
the year ahead is always better to see
the year ahead what is gone is fast but
one should realize the mistakes from
that and um
correct oneself for the future i request
something that the company takes into
not only i say lombard but all the icsi
companies should take into consideration
that i see that the agm is meant for the
shareholders and not for anyone
importance must be given to shareholders
at the time of agm thank you very much i
hope
the board of directors considers this
and takes
secretarial department has to be uh
tutored for this thank you all the very
best
[Music]
thank you mom our next speaker
shareholder is mr santosh sarah
mr santosh requests
foreign
[Laughter]
is
foreign
you
[Laughter]
foreign
thank you sir
our next speaker shareholder is mr vinod
mr vinod request you to unmute yourself
and proceed
i am starting my video also
yes
[Laughter]
the pet was down due to i think that's
mostly due to higher poverty
that would have come to the company and
because speaking of these phones
has claims having
it has gotten an impact on
the premium
rising for the health insurance
last year
in the first half you did the less of
motor vehicle due to supply chain issues
and this thing but uh
claims coming
for health which are not anticipated
at the time of writing of a policy
that would impact the profitability of
the company overall this is my take on
it and i congratulate the company for
all the awards in the college that the
company has got
mentioned on pages 10 to 13 i don't want
to mention that because they can be
easily seen on page 10 to 13. i also
have seen that the company has been
used some of the 34.25 crore on the csr
activity which is a very large sensor i
i'm happy about that and about the final
division you have given uh two dividends
one in term of four and the final
dividend of pi rupees which is good sir
we always would like to have more
dividend if we i hope the company will
have more profits in this year with
lesser amount of poet claims coming and
even the lesser amount of
maybe motor vehicle claims
in motor vehicles i think so the prices
of vehicles are going up so
comparatively the vehicle cost would
come the premium will increase but when
the settlement for the claim would come
that also would be on a higher side
because the vehicle cost in itself is a
little higher
so claiming a
claim which comes on a higher cost
vehicle could also be a little higher so
what is your take on the increasing and
for safe premium loan vehicle sir
i wish the company all the best signing
off
from mumbai i'll be pre i also thank
rima from the company secretary team she
was very helpful in making me join this
meeting
thank you sir
mr youssef request you to unmute
yourself
and proceed with my voicemail can you
hear my voice perfect can
[Applause]
11 page number ten eleven twelve we have
a vf we have won many ourselves best
general insurance award first indian
cooperative governance snack food award
asia most trusted brand general
insurance and who are the main company
in the same business
around we have declared two divisions
finally we run five rupees international
four rupees which makes two
which makes two or nine rupees and i
also thanks our rema from
foreign
a football player is playing so this is
how our company is growing up i like
[Laughter]
i am very happy to be part of the
excellent companies i don't know what to
say i'm very happy and i'm very
happy of this company that thank you
very much may god bless our company once
more i will thank our vikasan lima madam
and his full team for giving me a
balance here giving me a chance to be in
this set my photos are can you give me
one minute
i will start my photos
give me please
thank you
thank you sir our next speaker
shareholder is miss prakash nishinoy
mr kashmi request you to
from bombay respected honourable
chairperson
mrs lalita gupta d are the dignitaries
on the board and my fellow shareholders
good afternoon to all of you i received
the annual report well in time which is
colorful transparent informative
knowledgeable and contains all the
informations as for the corporate
governors i thank mr vikas mehta for the
same
i should not forget to thank miss rima
for phoning me and giving me the
connection
today without which i would be in a
position to speak so once again thanks
to mr vikas and rema madam
the chairman had given a beautiful
note about the company and it's working
so
i'm glad to know that our company stands
second largest
insurance company in india
congratulations keep it up
i'm happy to know that the company has
robust performance during the year keep
it up
i am thankful to the board for
recommending dividend during the
financial year 2122 on the outset i
congratulate the management for getting
number of awards during the year this
shows the hard work and sincerity of
each and every staff
i am very happy to know that the company
has done outstanding work in the field
of csr activities during the year
so i have a few q madam i have few
questions my question number one
any new policy introduced this year
number two any group insurance policy
number three what is the profitability
of the company during the year number
four are we planning to progress towards
digital future
number five how many claims specifically
during the year
i wish the company good luck for a
bright future and pray god that the
prophet of the company shall reach the
peak in due course
madam
i i support all the resolutions put
forth in today's meeting thank you
thank you mr prakashi our next speaker
shareholder is mr aspie basanya
you know
mr aspie can you try turning off your
video and speak your internet is not
stable
okay
request
request here to come in a network area
and speak
we are unable to hear you clearly
move to the next speaker shareholder
mr um
yes sir you are audible please proceed
so
see
just hold on
yeah
so
thanks for allowing me to attend this
meeting
and this is address to lalitha gupta
thanks
i believe the governance pattern of
icici being honored
and practiced here
yeah so there are a lot of things which
i wish
the icic lombard governance has to work
in that
election which is completely missing
from the
regime which i have raised and
this the and last agm chairperson agreed
to
address those issues
so first of the issue is that uh
if you open up the last
agm mom i have raised the issue
regarding independent director the
merger
the atl this party exa live insurance
and a lot of other issues
and uh
i pledge that
after
raising even to the highest like bargain
the things are not being addressed
and no one has come back with the
meeting being arranged
come back with the clarifications
nothing has happened
five this corporate governance is
completely missing and which is
highlighted by first pikachu
and last that i the board of governors
about meet the chairman of the meeting
has assured me
in
during that meeting itself
that people will reach me out within
a couple of days
for last one year i am waiting for that
beach
and even fargo is aware of this
and i want
given this because
who is supposed to be the custodian of
our interest and the board of directors
in the agm regulations which are being
passed in mom which is being agreed in
the mgm are need to be respected
which i found is terribly missing
so i want the answer right now from
lalitha
where and the email id of your
independent directors and you so that he
can give this complaint and what is that
what is the action being taken again
against mr vikas arora
the company secretary of
uh ics and local because we have already
lost the trust
because he is just trying to suppress
the voice of their
military stakeholders
as well as giving a wrong impression the
wrong picture to the boat as well as to
us
so what is the action which is being
initiated i just want to know from
bhargav as well as from lalitha and down
from the board
thank you so we'll move to the next
speaker shareholder
and am i visible also
yes you are
invisible okay
uh thanks uh
chairperson uh madame
other board members and my fellow
surrounders sir i am anil parikh here
from bombay
i hope
you all are safe and fine at your
respective end
uh
since this is the third meeting in a row
where we cannot meet and greet
physically each other
and
we are meeting our video conference
my humble request to all all the board
members to kindly see
that next year if everything goes well
we can meet physically and greet each
other
when
all the buses and trains are overcrowded
marriage functions are overcrowded why
we cannot initiate physical meetings
that is my humble request to you
uh
secondly i would like to
congratulate our cs team
for doing excellent work as far as
investor relation is concerned uh mr
vikas mehra
madam
she was
very kind to help us out
and frequently she was calling us for to
attend this meeting
thank you madam and vikas
i have
annual report in my hand excellent
presentation of annual report
with all corporate governance and
disclosures followed
and it consists every minor details
about the balance sheet company picture
past and present
many congratulations cs team for doing a
wonderful job
and uh
which can avoid many questions
i also would like to congratulate our
printer
we'll consume conceptualize
this
eco-friend with eco-friendly papers of
this annual report
message altean
is also
very good their job they have done
now sir
now madam begin with i also liked
page number four
wherein
uh
concept is given
that
reporting reporting period score
everything is very good which every
other company should follow on page four
uh on page seven our
uh what is the claim settled
under all uh all seven categories and
specially
during the commit time
we have seven verticals uh
of business and any more verticals we
would like to add here i would like to
know
and i also liked our company's
customer-centric approach
very good madam
on page eight and nine
uh going through the financials
excellent all-round performance
under the circumstances and economic
challenge
however
our
investment assets has gone down
even solvency ratio has gone down that's
very good and
return on average equity is also gone
down
madam we can
avoid using your terms as
billion and million rather we can use
drawers and lags if possible
that would ease for reading
and
i would like to congratulate management
for getting 22 awards under different
categories
superlative performance madam under
your guidance and capability
you are leading from the front and
truly
i can see human empowerment
in this company
so i would like to congratulate the
company and total management team
for
adopting
natural capital which i read on page 15
and
you are doing good
initiatives to improve health
environment and ecosystem
very good
one
and uh
last question i would like to have
on
what is the post covered situation of
the company and uh what do you foresee
top lane and bottom line this year thank
you for personal hearing and i support
all the resolutions strongly and once
again i thank our cs team vikas mehra
and rima chalvani thank you
miss arpita vijay varga
issues
raised by
mr
before i could complete
my
speaker
as seventh you people have muted me so i
strongly object this behavior from the
company's secretary team
and
let let the board tell me what is the
action they are taking right now against
the company secretary because i have
given multiple complaints against
company secretary which are not being
addressed
and this is the expectation was not
there that you you will stop me from
speaking you are suppressing the voice
of the minority stakeholder
which is not going to be tolerated
please mind so board
and the report chairman please let me
know what is the action you are taking
against the company secretary and
and
also against mr bhargav because we are
addressed we have addressed these things
to mr bargo multiple times and we have
got no response
no
neither we got the email ids or the
contact details of the independent
directors to take care of the things who
will escalate to the further things
chairman for chairperson
please let me know your email id also
so that i can escalate to you and this
is not expected behavior from and this
is against the corporate governance
which you people say we are following
the corporate governance which is not
being practiced in last one and a half
year on multiple instances mr vikas
has tried to because the company's
secretary tried to suppress the voice
and miss given the
misinterpretation to mr bhargava and mr
vargo after multiple escalation has not
acted against mr
company secretary or against our request
to honor those things which was agreed
again in the agm also
and in this agm also i i don't know how
this people has
muted me when i was speaking to and
allowed the other guys so it is the
clear instance
um obviously because these people have
acted
clearly on this
so let lalitha tell me what is the
action you are immediately
taking against mr argo the company
secretary and the secretary right now
that is complete
take off transparency there is complete
lack of independent director being
put in those
systems without due diligence and
deals which is there and there is a
related party transactions which are
happening which are totally
against any government
please let me know
what is your answer to this
i'm waiting for your answer
because the last atm these people agreed
and nobody reach out after multiple
escalations to mr bhargava even because
because
the company secretary
also
he was least bordered and
misrepresenting the thing facts and the
figure
mr amish we have not muted muted you
we have shifted to the next speaker
after your
[Music]
not speech
and that uh and you are just saying
neither apologist also apology there is
no apology from your side this is the
behavior accepted behavior
in this conference
so when we are talking to directly to
the director the board chairman
the chairperson of the meeting why you
are interrupting them
the chair person please let me know what
happened to my complaint last year
i have not got any response
from mr
escalated multiple times
about the theme i have not got the
response i want now
independent director's email id and
phone number also
hello
yeah
mr umesh
yeah tell me
the chili person i need on
now what happened to my complaint last
in last agm which which you people all
agreed
and people aren't like because he's not
ready to share the mi of the meeting
also
of the agm which is against any law of
the land
or
since this is against the law of the
land yes
violated the law of land what is the
action being initiated against the
company secretary
for suppressing the voice of the
shareholders
and why i need to wait for one and a
half year to get answer from you guys
after escalating to mr fargo
i don't don't know what dummy people you
people bring on the
this meeting also which i have seen
multiple dummy people you are allowing
the time
for cheryl shari also
thank you
with this we move to the love speaker
shareholder of the day this laykasa
hello
mom can you hear me
hello you are audible please proceed
thank you mom
madam
this is for my humble request for you
madame
respectively
mom board of directors and my fellow
members good afternoon to all of you
myself
mumbai
first of all i'm very much thankful to
our company secretary vikashi and
prima mom for sending the agent notice
building time which is full of knowledge
content in place
thank you mom for explaining us below
the company
congratulations for excellent work mom
mom i pray to god that he always
showered his blessing upon you mom our
company secretary vikashi
and rima ma
always answered all my calls and have
happily cleared my all my doubts
once again thank you so much bekashi and
rima mom
i had many questions to ask you
but they are all covered with the
previous speakers but they are
only two questions
at the outset i congratulate management
and esteem for the various award and
recognition received by the company
under the lambert employees
stock options granted on april 22 and 22
at what price guaranteed and quality
my second question is
in order to expand our distribution
network what initiative are taking
thanks for the dividend ma'am
so
i would like to say
i strongly support
all the resolutions for today's meeting
and my best wishes
always our company and this prosperity
thank you mom
thank you mr
with this
we will now allow mr aspie basanya who
was not able to speak earlier
mr aspie request you to unload yourself
can you help me now
yes you're honorable
okay
wherever i must be from bombay i would
like to know why you didn't call
physical meeting
because nowadays many companies are
holding physical meetings and i welcome
mr rakesh jah as a director and also i
welcome mr sandeep bhattaras resolution
i thank mr vikas mehra for allowing me
to speak at the meeting this is 22nd agm
in three years we'll be celebrating
silver jubilee so how do you propose to
celebrate silver jubilee or do you plan
well in advance
random q1 income has increased compared
to q4 of last year oh operating profit
has become one-third of
q for profit so what is the reason for
that
and madame agm is not the
forum for personal grievances personal
grievances have to be sorted out
outside the agm thank you very much and
all the best for the future
thank you sir with this we have
completed the speaker session i now hand
it over back to the chairperson to
conduct the further proceedings of the
agm thank you
now i request
mr bhargav dasgupta
managing director and ceo to respond to
the queries raised by the shareholders
uh thank you uh chairperson and thank
you all the speaker shareholders for
raising uh the questions uh i think they
were
this is chennai of the
in terms of the
positive experience that you had with
rima and vikas and the company security
team thank you for the feedback uh we
will obviously continue to see what we
can do to improve
uh i'll get into the specific question
that individually each one of you have
asked
mr patel your
suggestion on
a bit more engagement with the company
secondary team particularly during the
year is well taken we will see what we
can do you know we will i believe we try
to reach out but obviously we'll try to
was in terms of the market position so
if you look at our market position post
the integration with uh the bharti
acceptance that we acquired during the
last year we have moved from uh number
four company in the industry to number
two so we are now the second biggest uh
you know uh company in the industry
we've been number one among private
sector for a long long time but now
overall we are number two just behind
new india
in terms of
market share we are about eight point
one percent market share at the end of
the year
you had a very valid point about the
male female ratio uh and you know you
were advised to reduce the gap a point
absolutely taken we had roughly
and we hope that over the next three
years we will demonstrate that that
outcome there are targets that we've
taken internally there is a review that
happens with the board so this is a very
important agenda even for us but thank
you for pointing that out
you had a lot of questions around you
know i think the area of sustainability
you talked about rain water harvesting
we actually practiced that in our
corporate office
our branches you know we
we are looking at wherever we can we
don't use we are looking at improving
you know the consumption of
six offices will convert into complete
leds
and another 233 offices have partial led
lighting so there is a lot of focus uh
on this aspect as a company during the
year we've uh
uh
you know we branded renamed our csr
committee into csr and sustainability
committee and we are looking at this
issue uh very very actively as a company
and some of the initiatives that we are
taking is uh you probably have seen the
csl initiatives of implementing soda you
know setting up solar panels in some of
the
municipal schools uh just to ensure that
not only our own branches but even other
places we are
you know bringing in you know helping in
terms of promoting green energy
you had a suggestion in terms of
ensuring that even when we go physical
we keep it hybrid we'll keep that in
mind uh you know uh you know depending
on the situation the next year
so mr uh we know the other one you had a
few specific questions again you talked
about the fact that our premium has gone
up last year but the pat has come down
and you rightly identified this is
largely because of the uh the the covet
claims that we paid last year uh the
total claims that we paid for covet was
about uh 556 5.56 billion uh and your
question on what have we done in terms
of premium you know consequently that we
increase the premium for group policies
to the extent that we thought was
uh and make it more sustainable
now you also had a question on on motor
insurance uh motor
you know motor insurance you're right in
the sense that the price of vehicles are
increasing the premium also
commensurately increases to some extent
uh you know in line with that uh but
we'll also have to observe the claim
frequency because last two years we had
some reduction in claim frequency uh
because of partial lockdowns etcetera
during the year but this year the claim
frequencies are up and you know as you
know our principle has been to focus on
balancing top line and bottom then and
we'll keep on looking at what we need to
do in terms of making that portfolio uh
and as i explained we are number two
number one companies in new india just
after us there are a couple of
government companies like united
national orient oriental and then there
are private sector companies uh also you
want a confirmation that the total
dividend was is five plus four nine
rupees that is confirmed that is what we
uh we are paying out now your question
on the helmet if you see our uh the
helmet initiative is really part of our
csr initiative for ride to safety where
we go to municipal schools and do a lot
of workshops on importance of road
safety
and try to
out of that we give the helmets to uh
you know those uh you know individuals
they are not our customers not our
employees it's part of our csr
initiatives uh and that's why and the
issue has been going on for quite a few
years that's why you see so many people
writing with those helmets
you know you had some sensations on
independent days we are uh you know as a
organization we are hosting flags across
the country you will see lot of effort
that we are putting in the corporate
office so yes this is a very important
uh year in terms of the 75th year of
independence and we do want to celebrate
it you know in a large scale uh you had
some suggestions for the 25th agent
we'll keep that in mind uh if it is
feasible one of the things that we keep
saying that you know as a financial
service
value achieved strength to build a
sustainable business so we have to keep
all of that in mind when we think about
uh you know issuing bonuses etc
uh
miss chennai had again uh you know some
specific questions on
uh whether there are you know what are
the new policies introduced you know
last year we introduced uh i don't know
if you saw the ads that we were playing
while we were waiting for the agm to
start
we
introduced a very innovative product for
cashless outpatient uh you know health
claims uh traditionally health insurance
pays for hospitalization cost but the
normal
the overall healthcare cost in this
country is in that area so that was an
area where we launched a product uh you
know very innovative very uh different
from what traditional health insurance
companies you know do uh this year as we
speak uh we've launched some very
innovative voter insurance products
which you probably would have you know
read in the papers but that's this year
we will see how they do in the coming
year
you also
talked about what we are doing about our
digital future i think this is a big
thrust area for us as a company we've
always believed in
uh investing ahead of the curve on on
technology and digital and that's an
investment that we've continued to do
almost 97 percent of our policies that
we issue in the company we don't see the
paper coming in in the company
everything is issued uh you know outside
the organization through uh you know
through technology platforms or you know
e-commerce platforms or digital
platforms
we've also done a lot of work in terms
of using artificial intelligence and
machine learning to streamline the
process for settling claims uh again
using technology as also policy issuance
so that's an area that we keep on
investing and you know last year we
became the first
company large insurance company to move
all our systems to the cloud and that we
believe will help us in our digital
journey going ahead
you asked a question on number of claims
so if you look at the split motor we
played about paid about 1.3 million
claims health we paid seven million
claims and all others was about 0.3
million so totally adding up to about
2.3 million uh claims
uh mr vijay
you know you had a you know
you had a critique about the way they
the
the team the company secretary team has
been handling uh we believe the company
has provided you necessary responses
and clarifications from prime time your
time with respect to your concerns i'm
sorry that we still
all right again you had some you know
positive feedback about the annual
report like like
you had a question on claim settle plus
covet i think i've answered that both in
terms of numbers and povet as i said was
about 5.56 billion rupees of claims is
what we paid for uh covet in terms of
new verticals being added uh what we've
done this year uh post the annual report
uh you know uh or post the 31st march
is we've looked at uh you know creating
a separate group for
uh you know the emerging markets as we
call the smaller towns the hindu lands
the rural markets so that's a new
vertical that we've created but that is
this year
uh your question on investment assets uh
you know going down
that is uh
actually not correct because the total
investment assets have gone up from
thirty thousand eight hundred and ninety
two crores to thirty eight thousand
seven hundred eighty six girls uh over
the last one year you are correct in the
sense that the return on investment has
come down because as you as we've
discussed for the covet
you know due to covet losses our profits
for the year came down
and that's the reason why our roi has
come down
you requested for looking at pros and
lets we look at it but in general we
have been consistently using millions
and millions as a group and that's what
in the first four months the industry is
growing much faster
there is a bit of base effect so it may
not sustain for the whole year but the
initial months the growth is much higher
we are also seeing a lot more awareness
that has got created particularly in the
idea of health insurance and that growth
you know looks like it will sustain and
that's why we are also investing in in
adding more distribution in in
in that aspect
uh miss lakasha
you had a few questions uh particularly
in terms of distribution expansion uh
just to uh
you know give you a sense of what we are
doing
to
see people and you know and we've added
some more people in the first quarter of
this year these are people who then hire
agents and agents are the people who
actually go out and sell health
insurance on the agency side we are
adding uh we have added more than 8 000
agents and pos agents together in this
water so that's a you know focused
investment that we are taking as a as a
country uh we are adding a lot of
digital partners uh the number of
digital departments that we've had over
the last two years have significantly
increased we've added a lot of bank
issuance partners uh consequent to the
uh merger with martial so all those
banking partners have become our
partners that's also added a lot of
distribution
so overall there is a big focus in terms
of increasing our distribution through
the tradition
we are going to the hinterlands of this
country so digital and distribution
expansion is
is
very very important in terms of the esop
grant price we have a very strict uh you
know
philosophy which is uh the previous
day's uh you know
ending uh stock market price uh you know
at the market close and that for the for
the is granted for last year was
1363.1 rupee per share
miss
bessania again you had a recommendation
of physical as i said depending upon the
situation next year and where things are
we will definitely look and look into it
uh you asked a question on profits
having dropped as i explained it's
largely because of the movement losses
that the industry as well and us
experience which
really was not something that any one of
us anticipated before before this
pandemic that happened so this was
obviously not priced into our products
but this was a very large hit that we
took as a company and as an industry
and i think that was our responsibility
and we took care of all of those
claims i think that's largely uh
all the questions that i have had
and there was one question that i missed
uh i think misha had a question on the
distribution i'll just give you the
numbers uh
so the total number of agents that we
ended the year with we started the year
with seventy three thousand five hundred
eleven agents and pos agents we ended
the year with eighty eight thousand five
hundred thirty nine agents and pos uh
agents so that's the growth that we've
had last year we are further added as i
said roughly about 8 000 agents in this
year
thank you thank you
the queries have now been answered as
mentioned earlier those who have not
passed their vote on the resolution set
foot in the notice may do so now as the
e-voting platform is available for next
half an hour
i declare the meeting as close as soon
as the voting on the resolution is being
completed by the members through ee
voting
i authorized one of the whole time
directors of the company or the company
secretary to declare the results of the
remote e-voting as well as for the
electronic voting done at the agent
today along with the scrutinizers report
the results will be announced within two
days from the conclusion of the meeting
that is on or before tuesday august 9
2022 to the stock exchanges and shall
also be disseminated on the website of
the company along with the scrutinizers
report
the same would be duly recorded as part
of the proceedings of the agm this
concludes the formal business of the
meeting
before i conclude on behalf of the
company i wish to place on record our
gratitude to all our shareholders
customers distributors and regulatory
authorities for their cooperation and
active participation in the proceedings
and for their valuable suggestions and
all their employees for their hard work
and commitment
i also as i conclude i would once again
like to thank you on behalf of all the
members of the board for your continued
trust and support in all our endeavors
and last of all i must wish you and your
families all the very best for a safer
and healthier tomorrow please take care
of yourself thank you
you